ELENA NURULLINA

New York, NY. Open to relocation to Florida | +1 (347) 9096471 | elenka san@yahoo.com linkedin.com/in/elena-nurullina | https://github.com/ElenkaSan | https://elenanurullina.vercel.app

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript, DOM Manipulation, Node.js, Express.js, React.js, Redux.js, HTML, CSS, Python, Flask, Jinja, SQL, PostgreSQL, SQLAlchemy, MongoDB, NoSQL, RESTful APIs, Ajax, Axios, jQuery, Bootstrap, MUI, Java, PHP. Testing: Jasmine, Jest, React Test Library, Unit Tests, DocTests.

SUMMARY

As a Full-Stack Software Engineer, have extensive experience in problem-solving and customer service. Self-motivated and knowledgeable, always willing to work diligently to achieve personal and team goals. My greatest strength is my ability to connect with people from all walks of life and to treat everyone with equal importance and respect. I am a kind and generous person with a positive can-do attitude, always striving to find creative solutions to problems and achieve the best results for my team and customers.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

All projects developed the mobile layout and created a media query for tablet and desktop versions.

• Recipe-Tips / Link https://recipe-tips.herokuapp.com/

Designed and developed a website that promotes a healthy lifestyle with food recipe search where users can sign up, save recipes, add notes, and food jokes, and create customized workouts. Implemented design and interaction using JavaScript, Bootstrap, Font Awesome, and raw CSS. Utilized HTML templates with Jinja and implemented forms using WTForms. Developed APIs following RESTful standards and implemented Flask WTForm for CSRF security, secure back-end APIs using SQL server-side and Python Flask with session authentication. *Technology:* Python, Flask, SQLAlchemy, RESTful APIs.

• React-Jobly / Link https://tearful-cactus.surge.sh/

An application that allows users to register, log in, search, explore, view companies, apply for listed jobs, and edit their profiles. *Technology:* A single-page React, Node.js, Express.js. The app implements-based authorization using JWTs and manages data validation with JSON schema.

• Vacation-Time / Link https://changeable-laugh.surge.sh/

This is a full-stack, responsive application allowing users to search for flights and hotels, check the weather, users can sign up, then add notes, and activate countdown trip dates. Designed, built, and implemented React.js components for the web application's front-end, scalable Express.js APIs, following DRY principles and RESTful standards. Implemented secure authentication and authorization using JWT authentication and Bcrypt for password hashing. Utilized PostgreSQL as the backend database for efficient data storage and retrieval. *Technology:* React, Node.js, Express.js, RESTful APIs.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Peer Mentor / Springboard (May 2023 - Current), Volunteering

- Answer students' questions in Slack weekly and offer availability for students to reach out and ask for help/connect with them.
- Post helpful resources and encourage students weekly by sharing learnings, and best practices.

Full-Stack Developer / Development Center - Formats (September 2022 - Current)

Building a full-stack Coaching Website for the multi-format development center "Formats". This website is about professional coaching for students & adults, personal coaching for kids, and corporate business training.

- Developed wireframes based on client requirements, ensuring a seamless user experience using JavaScript, React, Node.js, Express.js, PostgreSQL, and Bootstrap.
- Implemented a data fetching and parsing system to extract and format analytic data, then integrated it into React components.
- Supported the entire application lifecycle, from concept and design to testing, release, and ongoing support.
- Demonstrated critical thinking skills by offering technical guidance and mentoring in UX/UI design.
- Ensured the application's stability, performance, and security through thorough testing and continuous monitoring.
- Stayed up-to-date with industry trends and emerging technologies, incorporating them into the development process when appropriate.

- Effectively communicated with clients to understand their needs and provide solutions that meet their requirements.
- Actively participated in code reviews and provided constructive feedback to maintain code quality and ensure best practices.
- Contributed to the overall growth and success of the coaching company by consistently delivering high-quality, user-friendly applications.

Software Engineering Track - Fellow / Springboard (February 2021 - November 2022)

A 700-hour course covers key aspects of front-end web development, back-end web development, databases, and data structures and algorithms, with 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight, and completion of 4 in-depth portfolio projects. Modules include learning resources, practice exercises, projects, and career-related coursework.

- Mastered skills in front-end web development, back-end web development, databases, and data structures and algorithms.
- Completed training in programming languages such as JavaScript, DOM manipulation and the JavaScript object model, Node.js, Express.js, SPA framework React, Redux, HTML, CSS, designing and consuming RESTful APIs, Ajax, jQuery, Python, Flask, SQL, PostgreSQL, and Git/Terminal/GitHub.
- Implemented integration of REST APIs and third-party services (Amadeus, Weather, Spoonacular).
- Designed and implemented responsive and user-friendly features with Bootstrap.

Full-Stack Web Developer / IPTC (Infrastructure Planning Technology Solutions) (June 2020 - March 2022)

- Developed and implemented SEO strategies.
- Built and customized websites using CMS platforms, incorporating responsive design and SEO optimization.
- Familiarity with CRM applications for customer relationship management and effective communication.
- Utilized HTML, CSS, Python, and front-end frameworks to create interactive and user-friendly web interfaces.
- Documented code, processes, and project-related information to enhance collaboration and knowledge sharing within the team.
- Actively contributed to agile development methodologies, participating in sprint planning, stand-ups, and code reviews.

Top sales manager / Travel Agency (May 2015 - March 2020)

- Providing sales, customer counseling, and new advertising strategies.
- Consultation on financial products for individuals. Bank loan processing.

In 2015 improved sales four times and was keeping this level in subsequent years. Got recognition as best sales manager.

Associate Banker Teller / JPMorgan Chase & Co (September 2017 - September 2019)

- The initial contact for many customers as they complete their banking needs to work toward their financial goals.
- Build meaningful relationships with clients and educate customers on Chase banking technologies.
- Calls to the back office for clients for their problem-solving, helping them with everyday transactions.
- Being an interpreter Rus-Eng-Rus for my colleagues with clients.

Received recognition from colleagues for creating great customer experiences by always being courteous, professional, and customer-obsessed.

EDUCATION

Springboard, Software Engineering Program / Certificate

Intensive course in Software Engineering methodologies and technologies

IBM Skills Network, Introduction to DevOps / Certificate

Google, Foundations of User Experience (UX) Design & Start the UX Design Process / Certificates

AWS Fundamentals: Building Serverless Applications / Certificate

Forage, Software Engineering Lite Virtual Experience Program JPMorgan Chase & Co. / Certificate

Tyumen State University, Institute of State and Law / Master's Degree

Major field of studies: Economics. Expert in Taxation

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Languages: English, Russian. **Driver's License:** Category B

Hobbies & activities: Painting & creative handmade products from my artworks, tourism & travel.